Edgar Sousa

Software Developer

CONTACT Phone: +351 919665037

Email: stratulatedgar@gmail.com

Github LinkedIn

ABOUT ME

I'm a junior software developer studying for a CTESP in web and multimedia development at IPCA. I have solid skills in programming, web development and database management.

I took part in school projects such as WeatherMovieApplication , which gave me practical experience in Node.js, Express.js and Supabase. I've also carried out other personal projects in Express.js and React.js. I've also done internships at Otelec on Erasmus+ and at TMG Automotive

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Back-end Node.js, Express.js

Front-end HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS

Databases Supabase, mySQL

Tools Postman, Insomnia, Git, Github, Docker

EDUCATION

IPCA (Instituto Politécnico do Cávado e do Ave)

2023 - Ongoing

CTESP in web and multimedia development

- Projects: PersonalPortfolio, WeatherMovieApplication, API-ContactList
- Technologies: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Supabase, Git, Docker

INA (Instituto Nun'Alvres)

2020 - 2023

Electronics, Automation and Computer Technician (Level IV)

Projects: CultiSmart

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Arduino

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pingo Doce - Santo Tirso

June 2024 - Present

Cashier Operator

Providing customer service and handling checkout operations efficiently.

TMG Automotive - Guimarães

August 2023 - September 2023

Industrial maintenance technician

 Performed industrial maintenance tasks as an electrician, ensuring proper operation of equipment.

Otelec - Erasmus + (Spain)

May 2023 - July 2023

Fiber Optic Installation Technician

 Carrying out tasks related to the installation of fiber optic networks in urban areas.

PROJECTS

WeatherMovieApplication

I've developed an application that dynamically combines weather information and movie suggestions.

Skills: HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, Supabase, Docker

· Links: github & docker hub

API Contact List

I have developed a simple API to manage a list of contacts. The API allows you to create, list and delete contacts, with the data stored in a .txt file.

Skills: Node.js, Express.js

· Links: github

LANGUAGES

Portuguese Native

English B1 Spanish A1